Guide to the Jack Randall Crawford Modern Drama Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Jack Randall Crawford Modern Drama Collection
1850-1979
DRA 10
Yale University Arts Library
53.75
(43 boxes)
Photographic prints and clippings relating to English and American Drama as collected by Jack Randall Crawford, the staff of the Drama Library, and others.
Crawford, Jack Randall, 1878-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Formerly housed in the Yale School of Drama Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Photographic prints and clippings relating to English and American Drama as collected by Jack Randall Crawford, the staff of the Drama Library, and others.
Arrangement
Arranged in ten series: I. Scenes from Early Plays to 1850. II. Scenes from American Plays, 1850-1979. III. Scenes from English Plays, (-1876)-1986. IV. Scenes from American Musical Comedies, (-1870)-1980. V. Scenes from English Musical Comedies, 1850-1971. VI. Designers (Scene, Costume, and Theatre Architects). VII. Costumes, (Greek-1953). VIII. Shakespeare's Plays, A-Z. IX. Film Scenes, Early Films-1979. X. Index.
Theater -- United States; Theater -- Great Britain; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York; Theaters; Theater programs; Theatrical paraphernalia; Actors; Actresses; Motion picture programs -- United States; Motion picture actors and actresses -- United States; Musicals; Theaters -- New York (State) -- New York; Theaters -- England -- London
- Scenes from Early Plays, Series I
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Scenes from Early Plays: A-Z to 1850 (Box 1)
- Scenes from American Plays, Series II
  - Scenes from American Plays (1850-1900) (Box 2)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1901-1906) (Box 3)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1907-1914) (Box 4)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1915-1920) (Box 5)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1921-1927) (Box 6)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1928-1935) (Box 7)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1936-1944) (Box 8)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1945-1953) (Box 9)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1954-1963) (Box 10)
  - Scenes from American Plays (1964-1979) (Box 11)
- Scenes from English Plays, Series III
  - Scenes from English Plays (circa 1876-1914) (Box 12)
  - Scenes from English Plays (1915-1926) (Box 13)
  - Scenes from English Plays (1927-1935) (Box 14)
  - Scenes from English Plays (1936-1947) (Box 15)
  - Scenes from English Plays (1948-1958) (Box 16)
  - Scenes from English Plays (1959-1965) (Box 17)
  - Scenes from English Plays (1966-1986) (Box 18)
- Scenes from American Musical Comedies, Series IV
  - Scenes from American Musical Comedies (circa 1870-1924) (Box 19)
  - Scenes from American Musical Comedies (1925-1952) (Box 20)
  - Scenes from American Musical Comedies (1953-1980) (Box 21)
- Scenes from English Musical Comedies, Series V
  - Scenes from English Musical Comedies (1815-1937) (Box 22)
  - Scenes from English Musical Comedies (1938-1971) (Box 23)
- Designers (Scene, Costume, and Theatre Architects), Series VI
  - Designers (Scene, Costume, and Theatre Architects): A-J (Box 24)
  - Designers (Scene, Costume, and Theatre Architects): K-Z (Box 25)
- Costumes, Series VII
  - Costumes (ancient Greece-1917) (Box 26)
  - Costumes (1918-1953) (Box 27)
- Shakespeare's Plays, A-Z, Series VIII
  - Stage Settings, Stagecraft, and Décor: A-Z (Box 28)
  - Shakespeare's Plays: All's Well That Ends Well-Julius Caesar (Box 29)
  - Shakespeare's Plays: King John-Richard II (Box 30)
  - Shakespeare's Plays: Richard III-A Winter's Tale (Box 31)
- Film Scenes, Series IX
  - Film Scenes (Early Films-1926) (Box 32)
  - Film Scenes (1927-1933) (Box 33)
  - Film Scenes (1934-1936) (Box 34)
  - Film Scenes (1937-1938) (Box 35)
  - Film Scenes (1939-1940) (Box 36)
  - Film Scenes (1941-1944) (Box 37)
  - Film Scenes (1945-1947) (Box 38)
  - Film Scenes (1948-1952) (Box 39)
  - Film Scenes (1953-1957) (Box 40)
  - Film Scenes (1958-1963) (Box 41)
  - Film Scenes (1964-1979) (Box 42)
- Index, Series X
  - Film Scenes A-G (Box 43, Folder 43 A)
  - Film Scenes H-P (Box 43, Folder 43 B)
  - Film Scenes Q-Z (Box 43, Folder 43 C)
  - Scenes from American Plays: (-1850 A-Z; 1850-1930 A-M) (Box 43, Folder 43 D)
  - Scenes from American Plays: (1850-1930 N-Z; Designers A-Z; Scenes from Shakespeare's Plays A-Z; Scenes from American Musical Comedies 1860-1913) (Box 43, Folder 43 E)